<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on TheTrophicLink</title>
    <link>/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on TheTrophicLink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An academic in business school, and being a better dad</title>
      <link>/posts/an-academic-in-business-school-and-being-a-better-dad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/an-academic-in-business-school-and-being-a-better-dad/</guid>
      <description>I’d never had formal management or leadership training, never been schooled in negotiation or influencing, and never run a business. I have now, and consequently have enhanced ability and confidence to lead teams, to navigate them through uncertain times, and, perhaps most importantly, to be a better dad.
During spring 2016 took part in the Fast Track Advanced Management Programme of Ashridge Executive Education. The Programme has two modules, each involves a one-week residential course at Ashridge, near Berkhamstead, just outside London.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Students are not our customers, they are our products</title>
      <link>/posts/students-are-not-our-customers-they-are-our-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/students-are-not-our-customers-they-are-our-products/</guid>
      <description>Universities are composed of two broad groups of individuals. The managers and the academics. The managers govern and lead; the academics do the teaching and research. Managers tend to view the University as a business, and academics tend to view the University as, well, not a business. (Some of the managers were academics, few of the academics were managers.)
When a viewing a University as a Business, the question “who are our customers” quickly arises.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculating FD</title>
      <link>/posts/calculating-fd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/calculating-fd/</guid>
      <description>Here you can get code and instruction on how to calculate FD, the measure of functional diversity that Owen and Kevin Gaston created.
Below is advice for using some code and functions in R that use the same matrix notation as in the original publication Petchey &amp;amp; Gaston (2002). The functions are updated to account for the development to FD we published in 2006.
Example 1  Get the code and example datasets.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food web tools</title>
      <link>/posts/food-web-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/food-web-tools/</guid>
      <description>Here you can get code to model and analyse food webs.
Download the code and example data files (and not the ADBM_shiny folder) for all of the above from this folder on github. None of this code comes with any guarantee. In fact its all pretty dirty and not optimised. Please contact Owen if you have suggestions or possible corrections.
All the code is written for R. We really can&amp;rsquo;t recommend it highly enough.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All the old posts</title>
      <link>/posts/all-the-old-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/all-the-old-posts/</guid>
      <description>Owen couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to easily and quickly move posts from the old wordpress site to this one. Here they all are as pdfs of the wordpress posts.
 About fairness in the workplace. About p-values. Back garden camera trap. Global net change in local plant biodiversity. Graduation day! Group retreat 2016. How to read ANCOVA summary tables in R. IEU Photo-Exhibition. Interesting papers 1. Interesting papers 2. Interesting papers 3.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making an effective enquiry</title>
      <link>/posts/making-an-effective-enquiry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/making-an-effective-enquiry/</guid>
      <description>Whether you are enquiring about available positions (and perhaps funding) or have a funding scheme that you would like to apply for (to be held in Owen’s group), there are a few things you can do to make it more likely that you get a useful response from Owen, or any other potential supporter.
 Include your CV with your enquiry, including names of any previous supervisors. Include a short statement of research interests and motivation, highlighting any outstanding acheivements.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>