<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TheTrophicLink on TheTrophicLink</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in TheTrophicLink on TheTrophicLink</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>A tool for valuing contributions in teams</title>
      <link>/posts/valuing-contributions-in-teams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/valuing-contributions-in-teams/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Working in teams can be some of the most stimulating, exciting, and important experiences we have. At other times things can get a bit sticky, for example when it comes to attributing rewards (e.g. deciding authorship and authorship order of publications arising). Hence proactive planning and assessing the contributions of members of our teams can be useful. In order to assist with this, a collaboration agreement is a very good idea. Also, teams may find useful this new tool for planning and assessing contributions in teams.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&#34;https://owenpetchey.shinyapps.io/valuing_contributions_in_teams/&#34;&gt;web application valuing contributions in teams&lt;/a&gt; summarises the contributions that a team can report in the associated &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/1hfpQblHZeAKTDYqYSvOw2E6eQ__Vp-n_NsOjcosfG5Y&#34;&gt;googlesheet Valuing contributions in teams&lt;/a&gt;. Below is a bit more detail about the problems and solutions being addressed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;in-the-googlesheet-you&#34;&gt;In the googlesheet you:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Specifiy project details that should be decided in collaboration with project members.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter the project name and the threshold contribution for authorship (or other reward scheme) in the project information sheet.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enter your team members into the sheet with that name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide on your contribution types and weights and enter information into the sheet of that name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Decide planned activities and enter the information into the sheet with that name&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;During the project enter realised contributions in the sheet with that name.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;problems-and-solutions-in-teams&#34;&gt;Problems and solutions in teams&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a number of challenges in team projects:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Authorship order is not sufficient to indicate and summarise what in reality are nuanced/continuous/diverse types of contributions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lack of transparency in team members efforts, which can lead to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.thecut.com/2017/04/what-to-do-when-you-feel-like-the-only-roommate-who-cleans.html&#34;&gt;overestimation of our contribution and underestimate of others&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Changes in contribution through course of a project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actual and intended contributions can deviate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Value from synergies challenging to account for.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Solutions for some of the problems above:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use Contributor Roles Taxonomy (CRediT Term) with degree of contribution (lead, equal, supporting); report this in publications.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Team accessible list of contributions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Tracked evolution of contributions, from intended to actual / final.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Transparent and flexible method for translating actual / final contributions into authorship order.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contributor responsibility for recording their own contributions(?).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project leader responsibility to ensure self-responsibility of contributors is understood, remembered and acted upon (e.g. develop research culture including these solutions; issue reminders).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An academic in business school, and being a better dad</title>
      <link>/posts/an-academic-in-business-school-and-being-a-better-dad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/an-academic-in-business-school-and-being-a-better-dad/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I’d never had formal management or leadership training, never been schooled in negotiation or influencing, and never run a business. I have now, and consequently have enhanced ability and confidence to lead teams, to navigate them through uncertain times, and, perhaps most importantly, to be a better dad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During spring 2016 took part in the Fast Track Advanced Management Programme of Ashridge Executive Education. The Programme has two modules, each involves a one-week residential course at Ashridge, near Berkhamstead, just outside London.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;wicked-problems-in-a-vuca-world&#34;&gt;Wicked problems in a VUCA world&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The industrial revolution led to times characterised by relative predictability. Design a television, make TVs, sell TVs, redesign TVs, make TVs, sell TVs. Manage the business to do that. That worked for at least half a century.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A foundation of leadership education at Ashridge is that we now live a VUCA world of wicked problems. VUCA is volatile, unpredictable, complex and ambiguous. Things will change, and we can´t predict how or when. Wicked problems have no single solution. Even the challenges we foresee will escape any single simple solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In such a world, leaders must draw on and nurture creativity. Team members need the high intrinsic motivation that comes from autonomy, from purpose, and from seeking mastery. Extrinsic motivation (e.g., performance related pay) and command-and-control leadership extinguish intrinsic motivation and the high levels of creativity arising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The research team I lead tackles wicked problems; in particular how can we more accurately forecast ecological dynamics, such as fish stocks ten years from now. So while I was familiar with the territory, I hadn’t connected it to leadership. Ashridge helped make that connection, and in doing so helped crystalise in me a personal leadership style that resonates with my research, that will bring out the best in team members, and which I understand and can develop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;running-a-business&#34;&gt;Running a business&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The programme included a business simulation taking place at the rate of one simulated year every real hour. My small team of classmates competed against four teams of other classmates. We designed, marketed, advertised, and sold retail products. The presence of the other teams created uncertainties about the outcome of our actions. We didn´t know what types of product they might produce, how hard they would advertise, the state of their finances. It’s a great testament to the programme that I played a key role in our company winning the competition (there were only four of us in the company, so we all played a key role).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’m happy that my team won, I think more often about the mistakes we made, about how we were successful, and what other teams did differently to us. As it turned out, we’d been making a rather serious mistake for the entire simulation, and had it continued longer, we probably would not have won.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most significant meta-lesson I took from the simulation was about what drives me. After we won, a classmate commented to me that I was probably highly competitive. I realised I don’t care about whether I am or not, because it is unimportant. Instead, I care about learning new things so that I can perform better than I could, about being creative, and about seeing others (and myself) attack the hardest problems we can find. It is nice, but for me relatively unimportant, that such behaviour often creates the greatest chance of winning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;collaborating-and-challenging&#34;&gt;Collaborating and challenging&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps my greatest concern was how I would get on with my classmates. Almost all were from the business world: managing director, development director, strategy director, vice president, financial controller, from a diversity of business sectors. How would I compare to them, would I make a fool of myself, what would they think of me? I was stepping way out of my familiar ivory tower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was challenged again and again. I had to ask what were P&amp;amp;L, KPIs, and B2B / B2C*. I probably said some stupid things. But I never felt any judgement from instructors or classmates. Quite the opposite. They were enthusiastic, supportive, open, observant, creative, and fun. The outstanding learning experience created by the excellent instructors was highly collaborative and challenged us all. We learned at least as much from each other as we did from the instructors. It gives me great optimism that these leaders in the business world focus on success through building supportive, safe, and authentic relationships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That sounds rather too warm and fluffy for business folk. True, none of my classmates were bankers, though one was a lawyer. Joking aside, all were highly driven, ambitious, and at times challenging. My optimism comes from seeing so many folk showing, believing, and demonstrating that giving is a powerful and probably necessary partner of drive, ambition, and disruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;being-a-better-dad&#34;&gt;Being a better dad&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before kids, life was relatively predictable and controllable. Get up at 7am, make breakfast, eat breakfast, read the paper, walk to work, work, go home, sleep, repeat. Now, none of those are certain: the arrival of my kids created volatility, uncertainty, complexity, and ambiguity. There are no simple or single obvious solutions to the challenges they create. And they themselves will grow up, live, and, with the leadership I may give, thrive in a VUCA world of wicked problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ndash; Owen Petchey, April 2016&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Students are not our customers, they are our products</title>
      <link>/posts/students-are-not-our-customers-they-are-our-products/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/students-are-not-our-customers-they-are-our-products/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Universities are composed of two broad groups of individuals. The managers and the academics. The managers govern and lead; the academics do the teaching and research. Managers tend to view the University as a business, and academics tend to view the University as, well, not a business. (Some of the managers were academics, few of the academics were managers.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When a viewing a University as a Business, the question “who are our customers” quickly arises. It is tempting to view the students as the customer. Though one might consider this accurate from a transactional perspective, it is a deeply disfunctional perspective.
A customer-provider relationship is not easily compatible with a good teach/mentor–student relationship. In particular, students-as-customers is not conducive to students taking responsibility for their learning. Perhap this is why it is quite unpalatable to many teachers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So don´t view the student as the customer. Don&amp;rsquo;t even think of a University as a Business. But if you really really want to apply a business perspective to a University (and I believe there are important reasons for doing so), view the student as the product, and their future employer as the customer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The University takes in relatively raw materials (new students) and transforms them into valuable products (graduates) by adding value (knowledge, skills, attitudes, relationships). These graduates have attributes (the product specification), and these are advertised to potential employers by their degree name, courses taken, and grade achieved. The attractiveness of the product (graduate) to the customer (the potential employer) is determined by match of desired and advertised skills (a match between employer desires and the employers perception of the product) , match between advertised and actual skills (underselling or overselling represent lack of match), and of brand perception (not all University degrees are regarded equally).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calculating FD</title>
      <link>/posts/calculating-fd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/calculating-fd/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Here you can get code and instruction on how to calculate FD, the measure of functional diversity that Owen and Kevin Gaston created.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below is advice for using some code and functions in R that use the same matrix notation as in the original publication &lt;a href=&#34;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1046/j.1461-0248.2002.00339.x/abstract&#34;&gt;Petchey &amp;amp; Gaston (2002)&lt;/a&gt;. The functions are updated to account for &lt;a href=&#34;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1461-0248.2006.00924.x/abstract&#34;&gt;the development&lt;/a&gt; to FD we published in 2006.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;example-1&#34;&gt;Example 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opetchey/dumping_ground/tree/master/functional_diversity&#34;&gt;code and example datasets&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gain an understanding of how to use R.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use the &lt;code&gt;dist&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;hclust&lt;/code&gt; functions to calculate a dendrogram from a trait matrix. Paste the &lt;code&gt;Xtree&lt;/code&gt; function into R. Use it to transform the object returned by &lt;code&gt;hclust&lt;/code&gt; into an object from which total branch is easy to calculate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The object returned by &lt;code&gt;Xtree&lt;/code&gt; is a list containing a species by branch matrix (H1) and a branch length vector (h2) (see &lt;a href=&#34;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1046/j.1461-0248.2002.00339.x/abstract&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Follow the methods in &lt;a href=&#34;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1046/j.1461-0248.2002.00339.x/abstract&#34;&gt;Petchey Gaston (2002)&lt;/a&gt; to get FD from H1 and h2.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The &lt;code&gt;FD.example.1.r&lt;/code&gt; file contains an example of using R to calculate the FD of a random community as it loses species; just paste the text into R. (Remember to paste in the &lt;code&gt;Xtree&lt;/code&gt; function!)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fd-example-2&#34;&gt;FD Example 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This example demonstrates what people have been asking about some: how to calculate the FD of communities that have different compositions, and see if those measures of FD correlate with a particular measure of ecosystem process (or community property).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Always use three data files as the foundation of these types of analysis. Each is created in xl, saved in xl, and saved as a comma delimited text file (extension .csv) because these are easily read into R. You should download all of these files to a particular directory. (Actually, you really need only the csv files.) The files are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The species by trait matrix: &lt;code&gt;species.traits.xls&lt;/code&gt; (Excel file) or &lt;code&gt;species.traits.csv&lt;/code&gt;(csv file). Here, the first column contains the names of the species and the remaining columns the traits.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The community composition matrix. &lt;code&gt;community.composition.xls&lt;/code&gt; (Excel file) &lt;code&gt;community.composition.csv&lt;/code&gt; (csv file). Species names must correspond with those in the species by trait matrix&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The community by functioning matrix. &lt;code&gt;community.functioning.xls&lt;/code&gt; (Excel file)  &lt;code&gt;community.functioning.csv&lt;/code&gt; (csv file). Community identifiers must correspond with those in the community composition matrix.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;code&gt;FD.example.2.r&lt;/code&gt; code shows how to calculate the FD of each community from the traits of species and see whether it looks like correlating with functioning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fd-example-3&#34;&gt;FD Example 3&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And finally, for now, there is a demonstration of differences between FD and variance calculated on a single trait. See the file &lt;code&gt;FDandvariance.r&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Food web tools</title>
      <link>/posts/food-web-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/food-web-tools/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Here you can get code to model and analyse the random, cascade, and niche food web models.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the code and example data files (and not the &lt;code&gt;ADBM_shiny&lt;/code&gt; folder) for all of the above from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/opetchey/dumping_ground/tree/master/random_cascade_niche&#34;&gt;this folder on github&lt;/a&gt;. None of this code comes with any guarantee. In fact its all pretty dirty and not optimised. Please contact Owen if you have suggestions or possible corrections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All the code is written for R. We really can&amp;rsquo;t recommend it highly enough. Virtually every type of ecological analysis is already available in the main distribution of R and/or the extra packages). R&amp;rsquo;s default graphics are of publication quality (and easily edited). Its free, will run on virtually any platform (e.g., Windows, Linux, Macs), and seems to be significantly faster than many other languages/environments. The only apparent down side is the steep learning curve. However, little steps easily tackle steep slopes; the effort will be rewarded. None of this code comes with any guarantee. In fact its all pretty dirty and not optimised. Please contact Owen if you have suggestions or possible corrections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of the things you can do with the code:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Model food webs using random, cascade, or niche algorithms.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Plot a predation matrix of the food web.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Calculate structural properties of food webs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;instructions&#34;&gt;Instructions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn how to use R(!).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get the code.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Source the file &lt;code&gt;FoodWebFunctions.r&lt;/code&gt; into R; it contains a bunch of food webby functions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Check out the code in &lt;code&gt;FoodWebExamples.r&lt;/code&gt; for an example of how to use the functions.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neo Martinez and Alice Boit recently showed me Network 3D. This is just a note to remind myself to write some instructions and code that can help me and perhaps others to move between the data format I’ve been using to store food webs, and a format easily read by Network 3D. Note that the R package cheddar has a function for formatting data for Network 3D.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All the old posts</title>
      <link>/posts/all-the-old-posts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/all-the-old-posts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Owen couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to easily and quickly move posts from the old wordpress site to this one. Here they all are as pdfs of the wordpress posts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink-About_fairness_in_the_workplace.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;About fairness in the workplace.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20About%20p-values.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;About p-values.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Back%20garden%20camera%20trap.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Back garden camera trap.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Global%20net%20change%20in%20local%20plant%20biodiversity_.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Global net change in local plant biodiversity.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Graduation%20day!.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Graduation day!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Group%20retreat%202016.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Group retreat 2016.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20How%20to%20read%20ANCOVA%20summary%20tables%20in%20R.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;How to read ANCOVA summary tables in R.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20IEU%20Photo-Exhibition.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;IEU Photo-Exhibition.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Interesting%20papers%201.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Interesting papers 1.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Interesting%20papers%202.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Interesting papers 2.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Interesting%20papers%203.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Interesting papers 3.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Interesting%20papers%204.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Interesting papers 4.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Interesting%20papers%205.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Interesting papers 5.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Interesting%20papers%206.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Interesting papers 6.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Interesting%20papers%207.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Interesting papers 7.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Interesting%20papers%208.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Interesting papers 8.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Interesting%20papers%209.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Interesting papers 9.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Interesting%20papers%2010.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Interesting papers 10.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Interesting%20papers%2011.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Interesting papers 11.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Interesting%20papers%2012.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Interesting papers 12.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20My%20first%20flipped%20classroom%20course.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;My first flipped classroom course.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Peer%20review%20in%20performance%20appraisals.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Peer review in performance appraisals.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Predation%20matrices.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Predation matrices.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Random%20resources%201.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Random resources 1.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Some%20books.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Some books.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Some%20notes%20on%20Principal%20Component%20Analysis.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Some notes on Principal Component Analysis.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20Testing%20the%20Metabolic%20Theory%20of%20Ecology_%20a%20simple%20pipeline%20using%20R_.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Testing the Metabolic Theory of Ecology_ a simple pipeline using R_.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20The%20art%20of%20advertising%20science-elevator%20pitches.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The art of advertising science-elevator pitches.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;/old_posts/TheTrophicLink%20_%20When%20should%20I%20start%20giving_.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;When should I start giving.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Making an effective enquiry</title>
      <link>/posts/making-an-effective-enquiry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/making-an-effective-enquiry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whether you are enquiring about available positions (and perhaps funding) or have a funding scheme that you would like to apply for (to be held in Owen’s group), there are a few things you can do to make it more likely that you get a useful response from Owen, or any other potential supporter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include your CV with your enquiry, including names of any previous supervisors.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include a short statement of research interests and motivation, highlighting any outstanding acheivements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Include a statement about the research you propose and how this research fits well with the supervisor’s / group’s.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be explicit about the funding source(s) you have in mind. Link to the funding scheme web pages you have identified.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Begin enquiries at least one month before any deadlines; more time may be needed in many cases.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many enquiries to Owen do not adequately address the third or fourth point!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
